A Register of the Claude Paillat Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Research materials, 1863-1999 (Folder 1-414)
  - Tome V, 1940-1984 (Folder 166-168, 173-174, 212, 331, 367-368)
    - Lille, 1940 (Folder 368: 1-3)
    - La Capelle, 1940 (Folder 368: 4)
    - Note de Huntziger, 1940 (Folder 368: 5)
    - Attaque du général Altmayer, 1940 (Folder 368: 6)
    - Rapports du général Prioux, 1940 (Folder 368: 7)
    - Archives enterrées, 1940 (Folder 368: 8)
    - Étude Cossé-Brissace, 1940 (Folder 368: 9)
    - 12ème Division d'Infanterie Motorisée, 1976 (Folder 368: 10)
    - Forces terrestres antiaériennes, 1940 (Folder 368: 11)
    - Direction des Étapes, 1953 (Folder 368: 12)
    - Artillerie, 1940 (Folder 368: 13-14)
    - Transmissions, 1940 (Folder 368: 15)
  - Tome V, 1985-1986 (Folder 210)
    - Verdier, Jacques, 1985 (Folder 210: 1)
    - Recherches iconographiques, 1985-1986 (Folder 210: 2)
  - Tome VI, 1929-1986 (Folder 116-120)
    - Gendarmerie, 1940-1941 (Folder 168)
      - Synthèses des rapports mensuels, 1940-1941 (Folder 116)
        - 1940 (Folder 116: 1)
        - 1941 (Folder 116: 2-3)
      - Légions, 1940-1942 (Folder 116-117)
        - Paris, 1941-1942 (Folder 116: 4)
        - 1ère, 1941 (Folder 116: 5)
        - 10ème, 1940-1942 (Folder 116: 6)
        - 11ème, 1940-1942 (Folder 116: 7)
        - 13ème, 1940-1942 (Folder 116: 8)
        - 14ème, 1940-1942 (Folder 116: 9)
        - 15ème, 1940-1942 (Folder 116: 10-11)
        - 16ème, 1940-1942 (Folder 117: 1-2)
    - Mers-el-Kébir, 1940-1941 (Folder 117)
      - 1940 (Folder 117: 3-5)
      - 1941 (Folder 117: 6)
    - d'Harcourt, Armand, 1929-1942 (Folder 117)
      - 1929-1942 (Folder 117: 7)
      - 1940 (Folder 117: 8)
    - Entretiens, 1986 (Folder 117)
      - d'Harcourt, Guillaume, 1986 (Folder 117: 9)
      - Raphaël-Leygues, Jacques, 1986 (Folder 117: 10)
    - Régime de Vichy, 1940-1943 (Folder 117)
      - Générale, 1940-1943 (Folder 117: 11)
      - Armée, 1940-1942 (Folder 117-118)
        - 1940 (Folder 117: 12)
        - 1941-1942 (Folder 118: 1)
      - Armistice, 1940 (Folder 118: 2)
      - Matériel de guerre, 1940-1942 (Folder 118: 3)
      - Espagne, 1941 (Folder 118: 4)
    - Forces françaises libres, 1942-1943 (Folder 118)
      - Bir Hakeim, 1942-1943 (Folder 118)
        - 1942 (Folder 118: 5-7)
        - 1943 (Folder 118: 8)
      - Afrique Française Libre, 1943 (Folder 118: 9-11)
    - Afrique du Nord, 1941-1942 (Folder 118)
      - Propagande, 1942 (Folder 118: 12)
      - Télégrammes, 1941-1942 (Folder 118: 13)
      - Juin, Alphonse, 1941 (Folder 118: 14)
    - Colonies, 1940-1942 (Folder 119)
      - Générale, 1940-1941 (Folder 119: 1)
      - Boisson, Pierre, 1942 (Folder 119: 2)
    - Commission allemande d'armistice, 1940 (Folder 119: 3-8)
    - Ministère de la Défense Nationale, 1940 (Folder 119: 9)
    - Contrôle des communications, 1940 (Folder 120: 1)
    - Territoires occupés, 1940-1941 (Folder 120)
      - 1940 (Folder 120: 2)
      - 1941 (Folder 120: 3-4)
    - Économie et main-d'œuvre, 1940-1942 (Folder 120)
      - 1940 (Folder 120: 5-6)
      - 1942 (Folder 120: 7)
  - Tome VI, 1939-1927 (Folder 171-172, 9, 96-97, 297)
    - Courrier Boulnois, 1986-1987 (Folder 171: 1)
    - Iconographie, 1939-1990 (Folder 171: 2)
    - Adresses et notes, 1986 (Folder 171: 3)
    - Courrier et notes, 1984-1986 (Folder 171: 4-5)
    - Notes, 1986-1987 (Folder 172: 1-9)
    - Témoignages, 1948-1986 (Folder 9)
      - Générale, 1948-1983 (Folder 9: 2)
      - Entretriens, 1986 (Folder 9)
        - Lemoigne, François-Yves, 1986 (Folder 9: 3)
        - Spitz, Charles, 1986 (Folder 9: 4)
        - Stenger, L., 1986 (Folder 9: 5)
    - Fonds Auphan, 1940-1973 (Folder 9)
      - 1940 (Folder 9: 6)
      - 1941 (Folder 9: 7)
      - 1942 (Folder 9: 8)
      - 1944 (Folder 9: 9)
      - 1949-1973 (Folder 9: 10)
    - Alsace-Lorraine, 1940-1941 (Folder 96: 6)
    - Bürckel, Joseph, 1987 (Folder 96: 7)
    - Entretiens et témoignages, 1986-1987 (Folder 96)
      - Charette, Madame de, 1987 (Folder 96: 8)
      - Mondanel, Pierre, 1986 (Folder 96: 9)
      - Thiam, [?], 1986-1987 (Folder 96)
        - 1986 (Folder 96: 10)
        - 1987 (Folder 96: 11-12)
    - Fornel de la Laurencie, Benoît Léon, 1940-1986 (Folder 96)
      - 1940 (Folder 96: 13)
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 96: 14)
      - 1986 (Folder 96: 15)
    - Rapport Chavin, 1940 (Folder 96: 16)
    - Collège d'Experts de la Défense Nationale, 1940 (Folder 97: 1)
    - Recherche scientifique, 1940 (Folder 97: 2)
    - Service du Travail, 1940 (Folder 97: 3)
    - Pétain, Philippe, 1940 (Folder 97: 4)
    - Colonies, 1940-1986 (Folder 97)
      - 1940 (Folder 97: 5-6)
      - 1941 (Folder 97: 7)
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 97: 8)
      - 1942 (Folder 97: 9)
    - Entretien avec M. Filoche, 1986 (Folder 97: 10)
    - Martin, Henry, 1940-1966 (Folder 297: 1)
    - Archives de l'Ain, 1989 (Folder 297: 2-3)
  - Tome VI-Recherches, 1939-1927 (Folder 107-108)
    - Générale, 1955-1987 (Folder 107: 4)
    - Nord, 1984-1986 (Folder 107: 5)
    - Est, 1986-1987 (Folder 107: 6)
    - Nantes et Bretagne, 1986-1987 (Folder 107: 7)
    - Colonies, 1986 (Folder 107: 8)
    - Levant, 1986-1987 (Folder 107: 9)
    - Marine, 1986 (Folder 107: 10)
    - Letourneau, Jean, 1986 (Folder 107: 11)
    - Allemagne, 1983-1986 (Folder 107: 12)
    - Belgique, 1970-1986 (Folder 107: 13)
    - États-Unis, 1940-1985 (Folder 108: 1)
    - Grande-Bretagne, 1957 (Folder 108: 2)
  - Tome VI-Recherches France, 1984-1985 (Folder 180: 7)
  - Tome VI-Wiesbaden et économie, 1940-1942 (Folder 315-316)
    - Commission italienne d'économie, 1940 (Folder 315: 10)
    - Délégation Française pour les Affaires Économiques, 1942 (Folder 316: 1-3)
  - Tome VII, 1940-1989 (Folder 199-200, 366-367, 346-347)
    - Entretien avec Jean-Pierre Busson, 1988 (Folder 199: 1)
    - Tunisie, 1943-1944 (Folder 199: 2)
    - Recherches, 1942-1991 (Folder 199: 3)
    - Diplomatie américaine, 1940-1985 (Folder 199-200)
      - 1940 (Folder 199: 4-6)
      - 1941 (Folder 199: 7)
      - 1942 (Folder 199: 8)
      - 1942 (Folder 200: 1)
      - 1955-1985 (Folder 200: 2)
    - Courrier, 1988-1989 (Folder 200: 3)
    - Archives de l'Ain, 1989 (Folder 366: 3)
    - Entretiens, 1988-1989 (Folder 366)
      - Bonhoure, [?], 1988 (Folder 366: 4)
      - Boulnois, Francis, 1988 (Folder 366: 5)
      - Busson, Jean Pierre, 1988 (Folder 366: 6)
      - Fourcaud, Pierre, 1988 (Folder 366: 7)
      - Garrigues, Albert, 1989 (Folder 366: 8)
      - Humbert, Jacques, 1988 (Folder 366: 9)
      - Roidot, Georges, 1988 (Folder 366: 10)
    - Procès des amiraux, 1988 (Folder 366: 11)
    - Situation militaire, 1942-1943 (Folder 366-367)
      - 1942 (Folder 366: 12)
      - 1942-1943 (Folder 367: 1)
      - 1943 (Folder 367: 2)
    - Vichy, 1942 (Folder 367: 3)
    - Bergeret, Jean, 1945-1988 (Folder 367: 4)
    - Darlan, François, 1942 (Folder 367: 5)
    - Laval, Pierre, 1942 (Folder 367: 6)
    - Boissau, [?], 1942-1988 (Folder 367: 7)
    - Algérie et Tunisie, 1942 (Folder 367: 8)
    - Télégrammes, 1940 (Folder 367: 9)
    - Landriau, Marcel Alfred, 1955 (Folder 367: 10)
    - Afrique du Nord, 1939-1942 (Folder 367: 11)
  - Tome VII, 1941-1990 (Folder 346-347)
    - Noguès, Auguste, 1941-1956 (Folder 346: 9)
    - Messerschmitt 262, 1980 (Folder 346: 10)
    - Correspondance, 1988 (Folder 346: 11)
    - Weygand, Maxime, 1960 (Folder 346: 12)
    - Politique de Vichy, 1942-1943 (Folder 347: 1)
    - Delmas, Jean, 1987 (Folder 347: 2)
    - Darlan, François, 1942-1950 (Folder 347: 3)
    - Jeantet, Gabriel, 1943 (Folder 347: 4)
    - Gaulle, Charles de, 1942 (Folder 347: 5)
    - Leclerc de Hauteclocque, Philippe, 1940-1990 (Folder 347: 6)
    - Destrem, Maja, L'aventure de Leclerc, 1984 (Folder 347: 7)
  - Tome VII, 1942-1989 (Folder 173)
    - Courrier Boulnois, 1989 (Folder 173: 1)
    - Notes, 1942-1989 (Folder 173)
      - Portraits, 1988-1989 (Folder 173: 2-3)
      - Campagne d'Italie, 1943-1944 (Folder 173: 4-5)
      - Campagne de Tunisie, 1942-1943 (Folder 173: 6-14)
  - Tome VII, 1943-1957 (Folder 210)
    - Négociations Giraud-De Gaulle, 1943 (Folder 210: 3)
    - Chevalier, Jacques, 1944-1955 (Folder 210: 4)
    - Entretien avec Georgie Auphan, 1986 (Folder 210: 5)
    - Auphan, Gabriel Paul, 1943-1955 (Folder 210: 6)
    - Pétain, Philippe, 1943 (Folder 210: 7)
    - Sainteny, Jean, 1954 (Folder 210: 8)
    - Barjot, Pierre, 1957 (Folder 210: 9)
    - Rollin, Henri, 1955 (Folder 210: 10)
    - André, Gérard, 1955 (Folder 210: 11)
  - Tome VII, 1988-1989 (Folder 235)
    - Générale, 1988-1989 (Folder 235: 1)
    - Courrier, 1988-1989 (Folder 235)
      - 1988 (Folder 235: 2)
      - 1989 (Folder 235: 3)
    - Boulnois, Francis, 1988-1989 (Folder 235: 4-7)
    - Entretien avec Roger Weil, 1989 (Folder 235: 8)
    - Recherches, 1988-1989 (Folder 235)
      - Archives de l'Ain, 1988-1989 (Folder 235: 9)
      - Nord, 1988 (Folder 235: 10)
      - Lecomte, Jean, 1988 (Folder 235: 11)
  - Tome VII-Toulon, 1942-1988 (Folder 410-411)
    - Mémoires de l'amiral Le Luc, 1952 (Folder 410: 10)
    - Destructions portuaires, 1944 (Folder 410: 11)
    - Rapport du colonel Nyo, 1942 (Folder 410: 12)
    - Écoutes et agences, 1942 (Folder 410: 13)
    - Article, 1942 (Folder 410: 14)
    - Témoignage allemand, 1943 (Folder 410: 15)
    - Rapports, 1942 (Folder 410: 16)
    - Situation du sabordage des bâtiments, 1942 (Folder 410: 17)
    - Évènements à Sète et Marseille, 1942 (Folder 410: 18)
    - Liste des bâtiments, 1942 (Folder 410: 19)
    - Sabordage de la flotte, 1942-1988 (Folder 410: 20)
    - Réfutation du rapport Marzin, 1944-1945 (Folder 411: 1)
    - Giraud, Henri, 1942 (Folder 411: 2)
    - Sabordages, 1942 (Folder 411: 3)
    - Lettre de l'amiral de Laborde, 1943 (Folder 411: 4)
    - Témoignages de marins, 1943 (Folder 411: 5)
    - Destructions de matériels, 1942 (Folder 411: 6)
    - Départ de trois sous-marins, 1943 (Folder 411: 7)
    - Rapport, 1942 (Folder 411: 8)
    - Entretiens entre de Laborde et des officiers allemands, 1942 (Folder 411: 9-10)
    - Rapport Favier, 1942 (Folder 411: 11)
    - Rapport du directeur du port, 1942 (Folder 411: 12)
    - Rapports des amiraux Lacroix, Bléhaut et Negadelle, 1942 (Folder 411: 13)
    - Rapports des commandants de batteries, 1942 (Folder 411: 14)
    - Boulnois, Francis, 1985 (Folder 411: 15)
  - Tome VIII, 1940-1985 (Folder 168-170)
    - Armée, 1940 (Folder 168: 26)
    - Boulnois, Francis, 1984-1985 (Folder 168)
      - Entretien, 1984 (Folder 168: 27)
      - Textes, 1984-1985 (Folder 168: 28-29)
    - d'Argenlieu, Georges Thierry, 1942-1960 (Folder 169)
      - Leclerc de Hauteclocque, Philippe, 1945-1952 (Folder 169: 1)
      - Gouvernement de Hanoï, 1942-1956 (Folder 169: 2)
      - "Chronique d'Indochine,", 1960 (Folder 169: 3-4)
      - Repiton-Preneuf, Paul, 1945-1951 (Folder 170: 1)
  - Tome VIII, 1945-1992 (Folder 246-249, 348)
    - Tribunaux militaires, 1948-1955 (Folder 246-247)
      - Bordeaux, 1951-1953 (Folder 246)
        - 1951 (Folder 246: 1-4)
        - 1952 (Folder 246: 5)
        - 1953 (Folder 246: 6-8)
      - Lyon, 1950 (Folder 247: 1)
      - Metz, 1949-1956 (Folder 247)
        - 1949 (Folder 247: 2-3)
        - 1950 (Folder 247: 4)
        - 1951 (Folder 247: 5)
        - 1952 (Folder 247: 6)
        - 1956 (Folder 247: 7)
      - Paris, 1948-1955 (Folder 247)
        - 1948-1949 (Folder 247: 8)
        - 1950 (Folder 247: 9)
        - 1951 (Folder 247: 10)
        - 1953 (Folder 247: 11)
        - 1954 (Folder 247: 12)
        - 1955 (Folder 247: 13)
      - Rennes, 1948 (Folder 247: 14)
    - d'Argenlieu, Georges Thierry, 1945-1949 (Folder 248-249)
      - Clarac, Achille, 1946-1947 (Folder 248)
        - Correspondance, 1946 (Folder 248: 1)
        - Rapports, 1946-1947 (Folder 248: 2-6)
      - Conférence de Dalat, 1946 (Folder 248: 7)
      - "Chronique d'Indochine,", 1947 (Folder 248: 8)
      - Indochine, 1945-1949 (Folder 248-249)
        - 1945 (Folder 248: 9)
        - 1946 (Folder 248: 10-11)
        - 1947 (Folder 249: 1-2)
        - 1948 (Folder 249: 3)
        - 1949 (Folder 249: 4)
    - Documentation militaire, 1945-1947 (Folder 348: 8)
    - Saint Marc, Hélie de, 1989 (Folder 348: 9-10)
    - Pervillé, Guy, 1992 (Folder 348: 11)
    - Parlange, Georges, 1973 (Folder 348: 12)
    - Entretien avec Laurent Beccaria, 1987 (Folder 348: 13)
    - Correspondance, 1988-1989 (Folder 348: 14)
  - Tome VIII, 1988-1992 (Folder 200, 404)
    - Britsch, Jacques, 1990 (Folder 200: 4)
    - Roidot, Georges, 1991 (Folder 200: 5)
    - Témoignages, 1988-1990 (Folder 200)
      - Huet, Philippe, 1990 (Folder 200: 6)
      - Humbert, Jacques, 1988 (Folder 200: 7)
    - Entretien avec Henri Jeanjan, 1988 (Folder 404: 1)
    - Corrèze, Jacques, 1991 (Folder 404: 2)
    - Gestapo, 1992 (Folder 404: 3)
  - Train à grande vitesse (TGV), 1990-1993 (Folder 201-202)
    - Cartes, 1990 (Folder 201: 1)
    - Coupures de presse, 1990-1993 (Folder 201)
      - 1990 (Folder 201: 2-3)
      - 1991 (Folder 201: 4)
      - 1992-1993 (Folder 201: 5)
    - Courrier, 1990 (Folder 201: 6-7)
    - Rapports, 1990-1992 (Folder 202)
      - 1990 (Folder 202: 1-2)
      - 1992 (Folder 202: 3)
  - Train à grande vitesse, 1990-1995 (Folder 282)
    - Générale, 1991-1993 (Folder 282: 1)
    - Courrier, 1994-1994 (Folder 282: 2)
    - Sustrac, Jacques, 1993 (Folder 282: 3)
    - Bujon, Maurice, 1993 (Folder 282: 4)
    - Rapports, 1990-1992 (Folder 282)
      - 1990 (Folder 282: 5)
      - 1992 (Folder 282: 6)
    - Publicité, 1994 (Folder 282: 7)
    - Rapports, 1992-1993 (Folder 282: 8)
  - Transmissions, 1919-1938 (Folder 14)
    - 1919-1926 (Folder 14: 1)
    - 1933-1937 (Folder 14: 2)
    - 1938 (Folder 14: 3)
  - Transports, 1963-1981 (Folder 48-49)
    - Société Nationale des Chemins de Fer Français (S.N.C.F.), 1969-1979 (Folder 48: 4)
    - Aérotrains, 1970-1974 (Folder 48: 5)
    - Turbotrains, 1971-1979 (Folder 48: 6)
    - Transports parisiens, 1970-1975 (Folder 48: 7)
    - Transports routiers, 1963-1975 (Folder 48: 8)
    - Tunnel sous la Manche, 1970-1975 (Folder 48: 9)
    - Transports maritimes, 1971-1979 (Folder 49: 1)
    - Train à grande vitesse (T.G.V.), 1981 (Folder 49: 2)
  - Tunisie, 1926-1937 (Folder 177)
    - Générale, 1926-1931 (Folder 177: 1)
    - Destours, 1936 (Folder 177: 2)
    - Analyses de la situation, 1936-1937 (Folder 177: 3)
    - Alger, 1936-1937 (Folder 177: 4)
    - Paris, 1936-1937 (Folder 177: 5)
  - Tunisie, 1937-1944 (Folder 8)
    - Analyses de la situation, 1938-1939 (Folder 8)
      - 1938 (Folder 8: 3)
      - 1939 (Folder 8: 4)
    - Bourguiba, Habib, 1937 (Folder 8: 5)
    - Correspondance, 1938-1943 (Folder 8: 6)
    - Renseignements, 1937-1944 (Folder 8)
      - 1937-1939 (Folder 8: 7)
      - 1940-1944 (Folder 8: 8)
  - Tunisie, 1943 (Folder 58)
    - Générale, 1943 (Folder 58: 1)
    - Commission d'enquête, 1943 (Folder 58: 2)
  - Tunisie, 1951-1954 (Folder 37)
    - Bourguiba, Habib, 1954 (Folder 37: 8)
    - Fellaghs, 1954 (Folder 37: 9)
    - Gromand, Roger, 1951 (Folder 37: 10)
    - Voizard, Pierre, 1953-1954 (Folder 37: 11)
  - Tunisie, rapports du consulat américain, 1930-1939 (Folder 267)
    - 1930 (Folder 267: 1)
    - 1931 (Folder 267: 2)
    - 1932 (Folder 267: 3)
    - 1933 (Folder 267: 4)
    - 1934 (Folder 267: 5)
    - 1935 (Folder 267: 6)
    - 1936 (Folder 267: 7)
    - 1937 (Folder 267: 8)
    - 1938 (Folder 267: 9)
    - 1939 (Folder 267: 10)
  - Union des Industries Métallurgiques Minières, 1951-1974 (Folder 232)
    - Pichon, Poughon, et Pluyette, 1960 (Folder 232: 30)
    - Entretien avec Pierre Waline, 1974 (Folder 232: 31)
    - Documentation Waline, 1951-1972 (Folder 232: 32)
  - Union des Intérêts Économiques, 1912-1944 (Folder 177-178)
    - Documentation La Gravière, 1912-1944 (Folder 177: 8-9)
    - Documentation La Gravière, 1912-1944 (Folder 178: 1-4)
    - Chambre des Députés, 1924 (Folder 178: 5)
  - Wiesbaden, 1941 (Folder 34: 10-12)
  - Wiesbaden, 1941 (Folder 35: 1-4)
  - Wendel, François de, 1975 (Folder 216)
    - Généalogie, 1975 (Folder 216: 1)
    - Jeanneney, Jean-Noël, "François de Wendel en République; l'argent et le pouvoir, 1914-1940,", 1975 (Folder 216: 2)
  - X-Crise, 1931-1980 (Folder 340-341)
    - Générale, 1934-1938 (Folder 340: 1)
    - X-Information, 1931-1932 (Folder 340)
      - 1931 (Folder 340: 2)
      - 1932 (Folder 340: 3)
    - X-Crise, 1933-1939 (Folder 340-341)
      - 1933 (Folder 340: 4)
      - 1934 (Folder 340: 5)
      - 1935 (Folder 340: 6)
      - 1936 (Folder 340: 7)
      - 1937 (Folder 340: 8)
      - 1938 (Folder 340: 9)
      - 1939 (Folder 341: 1)
    - Thèse, 1965 (Folder 341: 2)
    - Callot, Jean-Pierre, 1959 (Folder 341: 3)
    - Entretiens avec Jean Ullmo, 1975 (Folder 341: 4-6)
    - Nicoletis, John, 1977 (Folder 341: 7)
    - Loizillon, André, 1981 (Folder 341: 8)
    - Bardet, Gérard, 1974-1980 (Folder 341: 9)
- Oversize materials, 1919-1933 (Folder 415-416)
  Contains serial issues
  - Journaux, 1919-1933 (Folder 415-416)
    - Le Réveil économique, 1920-1933 (Folder 415)
      - 1920 (Folder 415: 1)
      - 1921 (Folder 415: 2)
      - 1922 (Folder 415: 3)
      - 1923 (Folder 415: 4)
      - 1924 (Folder 415: 5)
      - 1925 (Folder 415: 6)
      - 1926 (Folder 415: 7)
      - 1927 (Folder 415: 8)
      - 1928 (Folder 415: 9)
      - 1929 (Folder 415: 10)
      - 1930 (Folder 415: 11)
      - 1931 (Folder 415: 12)
      - 1932 (Folder 415: 13)
      - 1933 (Folder 415: 14)
    - l'Humanité, 1919 (Folder 416: 1)
    - Le Temps, 1925 (Folder 416: 2)
    - Le Quotidien, 1924 (Folder 416: 3)
    - Le Petit marseillais, 1919 (Folder 416: 4)
- Computer disks, 1990 (Folder 417)
  Contains sixteen 3.5 inch, 2 MB floppy disks with files of notes, correspondence, and writings by Claude Paillat
- Microfilm reels, 1970 (Folder 417)
  Contains five reels of microfilm of documents from the National Archives of the United States
- Correspondence, 1961-2000 (Folder 418-432)
  Contains letters in a general file, arranged chronologically, and an alphabetical file, arranged by name of correspondent
  - General, 1961-2000 (Folder 418-429)
    - 1961-1964 (Folder 418: 1)
    - 1965 (Folder 418: 2-4)
    - 1966 (Folder 418: 5-10)
    - 1966 (Folder 419: 1-2)
    - 1967 (Folder 419: 3-10)
    - 1967 (Folder 420: 1-4)
    - 1968 (Folder 420: 5-10)
    - 1969 (Folder 420: 11-12)
    - 1969 (Folder 421: 1-3)
    - 1970 (Folder 421: 4-5)
    - 1971 (Folder 421: 6)
    - 1972 (Folder 421: 7-8)
    - 1973 (Folder 421: 9-12)
    - 1974 (Folder 422: 1)
    - 1975 (Folder 422: 2-8)
    - 1976 (Folder 422: 9-11)
    - 1977 (Folder 423: 1-6)
    - 1978 (Folder 423: 7-9)
    - 1979 (Folder 423: 10-12)
    - 1979 (Folder 424: 1-2)
    - 1980 (Folder 424: 3-9)
    - 1981 (Folder 424: 10-12)
    - 1982 (Folder 425: 1-4)
    - 1984 (Folder 425: 5-8)
    - 1985 (Folder 425: 9-12)
    - 1986 (Folder 426: 1-5)
    - 1987 (Folder 426: 6)
    - 1988 (Folder 426: 7)
    - 1989 (Folder 426: 8-9)
    - 1990 (Folder 426: 10-12)
    - 1991 (Folder 427: 1-3)
    - 1992 (Folder 427: 4)
    - 1993 (Folder 427: 5-9)
    - 1994 (Folder 428: 1-3)
    - 1995 (Folder 428: 4-5)
    - 1996 (Folder 428: 6-9)
    - 1997 (Folder 428: 10-12)
    - 1998 (Folder 429: 1)
    - 1999 (Folder 429: 2-3)
    - 2000 (Folder 429: 4)
  - Benouville, Pierre de, 1986-1999 (Folder 429: 5)
  - Bounois, Francis, 1985-1986 (Folder 429: 6)
  - Clémentin, Jean, 1976-1986 (Folder 429: 7)
  - Culmann, Henri, 1975 (Folder 429: 8)
  - Éditions de la Table Ronde (Gabirel Jeantet, Roland Laudenbach), 1966-1970 (Folder 429: 9)
  - Éditions Denoël (Paul Gimard, Philippe Rossignol), 1968-1970 (Folder 429: 10)
  - Éditions Fayard (Constantin Melnik), 1967 (Folder 429: 11)
  - Éditions Réalités (Gaston d'Angelis), 1973 (Folder 429: 12)
  - Éditions Robert Laffont (Georges Belmont, Jacques Labour, Laurent Laffont, Robert Laffont, Claude Mahias, Jacques Peuchmaurd, Jean-Pierre Vivet), 1966-1995 (Folder 429-430)
    - 1966 (Folder 429: 13)
    - 1967 (Folder 429: 14)
    - 1968 (Folder 429: 15)
    - 1969-1975 (Folder 429: 16)
    - 1979 (Folder 429: 17)
    - 1981 (Folder 429: 18)
    - 1984 (Folder 430: 1)
    - 1985 (Folder 430: 2-3)
    - 1986 (Folder 430: 4)
    - 1987-1991 (Folder 430: 5)
    - 1992 (Folder 430: 6-8)
    - 1993 (Folder 430: 9)
    - 1994 (Folder 430: 10)
    - 1995 (Folder 430: 11)
  - Gantier, Gilbert, 1999 (Folder 431: 1)
  - Hiely, André, 1994-1995 (Folder 431: 2)
  - Jacquin, Maurice, 1969-1972 (Folder 431: 3)
  - Lambert, Guy, 1975 (Folder 431: 4)
  - Lecomte, Georges, 1973 (Folder 431: 5)
  - Librairie Flammarion (Henri Noguères), 1967 (Folder 431: 6)
  - Librairie Jules Tallandier (Jacques Charpier, Isabel de Lanzac, Christian Melchior-Bonnet, François-Xavier de Vivie), 1968-1972 (Folder 431: 7)
  - Messac, Ralph, 1986 (Folder 431: 8)
  - Paris Match (Dominique Eudes, Hubert d'Havrincourt), 1990 (Folder 431: 9-11)
  - Ross, Denise, 1991 (Folder 431: 12)
  - Schoeller, Guy, 1966-1967 (Folder 431: 13)
  - Simonard, André, 1984-1986 (Folder 431)
    - 1984 (Folder 431: 14)
    - 1985-1986 (Folder 431: 15)
  - Siritzky, Jo, 1969 (Folder 432: 1)
  - Soulé, Robert, 1991 (Folder 432: 2)
  - Syndicat National des Journalistes, 1986 (Folder 432: 3)
  - Yacono, Xavier, 1981 (Folder 432: 4)
  - Yrissou, Henri, 1996 (Folder 432: 5)
- Writings, 1961-1993 (Folder 432-453)
  Contains articles, correspondence, and typescripts of monographs, arranged chronologically
  - Dossier secret de l'Algérie, 1961 (Folder 432-433)
    - Notes, 1961 (Folder 432: 6)
    - Typescript drafts, 1961 (Folder 432: 7-12)
    - Typescript drafts, 1961 (Folder 433: 1-7)
  - L'Échiquier d'Alger, 1961 (Folder 434-435)
    - Chronology, 1961 (Folder 434: 1)
    - Typescript drafts, 1961 (Folder 434: 2-9)
    - Typescript drafts, 1961 (Folder 435: 1-12)
  - With Paul Lesourd, Dossier secret. L'Église de la France, 1966-1968 (Folder 436)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Folder 436)
      - 1966 (Folder 436: 1)
      - 1967 (Folder 436: 2)
      - 1968 (Folder 436: 3)
    - Summary, 1967 (Folder 436: 4)
    - Clippings, 1967-1968 (Folder 436)
      - 1967 (Folder 436: 5-6)
      - 1968 (Folder 436: 7)
    - Mailing lists, 1967 (Folder 436: 8)
  - "Il y a 25 ans: Darlan était assassiné" Historia, 1967 December (Folder 436: 9)
  - Archives secrètes 1968-69, les coulisses d'une année terrible, 1969 (Folder 436)
    - Clippings, 1969 (Folder 436: 10-11)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Folder 436: 12)
  - Vingt ans qui déchirèrent la France. La liquidation, 1968-1972 (Folder 437-439)
    - Typescript (incomplete), 1972 (Folder 437: 1-9)
    - Typescript (incomplete), 1972 (Folder 438: 1-3)
    - Clippings, 1972 (Folder 438: 4-5)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Folder 438)
      - 1968-1971 (Folder 438: 5-6)
      - 1972 (Folder 438: 7-10)
      - 1973 (Folder 439: 1)
    - Mailing lists, 1972 (Folder 439: 2)
  - "Mai 1958: le troisième coup d'état de de Gaulle," Historia, 1972 November (Folder 439: 3)
  - Article on Antoine Pinay, Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 4)
  - Article on French elections, Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 5)
  - Article on Georges Pompidou, Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 6)
  - Article on Valéry Giscard d'Estaing, Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 7)
  - "Carcasonne," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 8)
  - "Deux vieux B. B. en péril," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 9)
  - "Du côté de chez Dassault," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 10)
  - "Élections Méditerranée," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 11)
  - "Élections Toulouse," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 12)
  - "Justice," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 13)
  - "On reclasse à Bordeaux," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 14)
  - "Picasso," Le Canard enchaîné, 1973 (Folder 439: 15)